Guide to the John Betancourt Collection, 1993-2004 RL.11376
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John Betancourt collection
1980s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Betancourt, John
RL.11376
7.5 Linear Feet
Assorted zines, monographs, and other printed materials related to science fiction and fantasy collected by John Betancourt, science fiction author and former editor of Weird Tales.
Arrangement
Titles arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
John Gregory Betancourt (born October 25, 1963) is a writer and editor of science fiction, fantasy and mystery novels, and short stories.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Accession 2018-0035 (boxes 2-8) is closed until processing.
Provenance
The John Betancourt Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017 and 2018.
Related Materials
A number of monographs and books have been removed for individual cataloging in Rubenstein Library. The Rubenstein Library also holds the Lin Carter Papers, another gift by John Betancourt.
Collection Overview
Assorted fanzines and other science fiction literature collected and assembly by John Betancourt. Also includes assorted World Science Fiction Convention programs and some publications and drawings by Richard Levesque.
Fanzines; Science fiction; Speculative fiction; World Science Fiction Convention
- Dark Regions Press flyer (Box 1)
- dreams and nightmares, by Bob Grumman, 1994 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Issue no. 42
- File 770, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  Issues no. 98, 99, 100, 101, 102
- Heliocentric Net, Spring 1994 (Box 1)
  Volume 3, Issue 2
- It Goes on the Shelf, 1993 Oct., 1994 Jan. (Box 1)
  Issue no. 10 and 11
- The Joe Bob Report, 1994 Jan. (Box 1)
  Volume X, no. 1
- Levesque, Richard, 1993 (Box 1)
  Drawing and letter to Betancourt; Apolitical Body Farm (1993); Bone-Break Psychobilly Stew (1993).
- The New Jersey Graveline, 1994 March (Box 1)
  Volume 2, no. 3
- The Red Letter, March-June, 1994 (Box 1)
- Skeletal Remains, 1993 Oct. (Box 1)
  Issue 3
- Tangent, 1994 (Box 1)
  Volume 1, no. 6
- True Review, 1994 Oct. (Box 1)
  Volume 6, no. 4
- The Weirdbook Appendix (from Weirdbook 28) (Box 1)
- World Science Fiction Convention (programs), 1989, 1992, 2002, 2004 (Box 1)
  The 47th, 50th, 60th, and 62nd World Science Fiction Convention
- Accession 2018-0035. (Box 2-8)
  Unprocessed manuscripts, Wildside Press records, papers relating to SFWA, fanzines, and bulletins.
  Conditions Governing Access
  This accession is closed until processing.